#### CONTACT DETAILS



in

www.linkedin.com/in/Christopher-sullivan-b0834a75/



## Why choose me?

An enthusiastic and multi-faceted software developer with a breadth of experience in Information Technology which has included roles in support, consultancy and software development working as an individual and part of a team.

Technically assured, committed and focused I am a motivated self-starter who is quick to learn new technology and business domains. Whilst I like to push the boundaries technically I'm also dedicated to choosing the right solution for a given business requirement and provide a pragmatic approach taking into account delivery schedules, team abilities and business goals. Being an advocate of Agile working practices, I promote open communication, fast feedback, lean code, delivery pipelines, knowledge sharing, continual team improvement and Kaizen.

Over the course of my career I have managed small teams and enjoy overseeing the delivery of a product but feel I'm best suited to concentrating on the key issue of developing software and relish the opportunity to be part of an innovative and progressive company who offer genuine value to their customers.

# Languages / Skills

<b>C</b> #	• • • •	Go	• • • • •
Ruby	• • • • •	HTML/CSS	• • • • •
JavaScript	• • • • •	SQL	• • • • •
DevOps			

# Technical Knowledge

Database SQL Server, MySQL

DevOps AWS, Docker, Terraform, Chef, Vagrant
CI / CD Jenkins, Cruise Control, Circle CI
Environments MS Windows, RHEL CentOS, Ubuntu

Tools Git, SVN, Team Foundation Server, Advanced Installer, NUnit, Rspec, Bash, PowerShell

Miscellaneous Jira, Pivotal Tracker, RabbitMQ, NGINX

### **Education**

MCP Visual Foxpro, HNC Software Engineering, Various City and Guilds 726 certificates, RSA Information Technology, 8 O Levels

### Miscellaneous

An essential part of my career development is to strive for continual improvement by studying my discipline and adding value to the workplace. Additionally, where I feel I have the skills I contribute to open source projects with bug fixes or assistance with issues.

Last technical books read: Large Scale Scrum, Your Code as a Crime Scene, Python Machine Learning Current personal projects and interests: JRuby, Go, newSQL, WebAssembly, gRPC

# Christopher **Sullivan**

Software Developer

### Working Experience

Present Oct 2017

## **Senior Software Engineer**

Sage

Winnersh

October 2017 – Present RTX Adapter – Nodejs, NPM, Mocha, Instanbul, Should, Sinon, Swagger

Added new modules to an existing Nodejs application, extended unit and integration test and code coverage.

April 2012 Oct 2017

### **Senior Software Developer**

NewVoiceMedia

Basingstoke

2015 - October 2017 - Technical Lead - DevOps, Chef, Ruby, PowerShell, AWS, Docker

Brought my Software Engineering skills to the Operations team, taking charge of delivering automation which includes infrastructure as code (Terraform with AWS), desired state configuration (Chef/PowerShell) and simplified product release process by creating an automated pipeline (Jenkins/Chef/Custom tools) with a standardised build language (Rake). Implemented custom services (Rack/Sinatra/Grape) situated behind NGINX to support the infrastructure. Last project delivered microservices in Docker containers running on Amazon ECS including and modelling the components of the companies API gateway.

2013 - 2015 - Call Control - C#, MySQL

Creating event services and notification handlers to allow publish and subscribe messages from low level telephony services to be handled by the core product. Added value objects (Domain Driven Design) to the code base, changed the number handling routines to use E.164 format and move towards display of telephone numbers in E.123 format.

2012 - 2013 - UI Feature team - C#, JavaScript, MySQL

Working on the company's core product, identified and implemented various cross cutting concerns, including CQRS directing non critical reads to use a slave database, template based (Bootstrap) UI improvements and creating bulk modification administration screens. Facilitated and ran lunchtime learning (brown bag) sessions.

2004 Until 2012

### **Lead Developer**

NorthgateArinso

Marlow

Designed and architected several green field .Net solutions, delivered on time and to budget. Achievements include introducing the use of design patterns to the team, mentoring developers and building a resource library.

2011 - 2012 - Mobile application - C#, Silverlight, MVVM, SQL Server

Taking the product to the next level we were looking to innovate with alternatives to desktop and web by providing functionality for Windows Phone users.

2006 – 2011 - ASP .Net, JavaScript, Windows Forms, .Net Custom Controls and Customisation tools, SQL Server

Lead a team that built traditional three tier application written in ASP .Net including a business framework with custom controls. The goals were to allow the software to be both upgradeable and customised by third parties.

Building on top of our business framework and being influenced by the Smart Client Software Factory we produced a Windows Shell that dynamically loads a Windows Forms UI environment providing parity with the web application.

2001 -2004	Senior Software Developer	Microsoft	Reading
2000 -2001	Principal Consultant	Documentum	▼ Uxbridge
1998 -2000	Principal Consultant	PWA Personnel Systems	▼ Marlow
1996 -1998	Technical Team Lead	Highams	▼ Caterham
1994 -1196	Software Developer	Churchill Retail Solutions	▼ Frimley
1990 -1993	Software Developer	KSE Computers	▼ Chertsey
1987 -1990	Support Developer	Custom Maintenance Systems	▼ Bodmin